<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nuhova Kamila Ruslanovna</title>
    <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://krnuhova.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nuhova Kamila Ruslanovna</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://krnuhova.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Nuhova Kamila Ruslanovna</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Hugo Blox Builder&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/content-types/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Personal Website for a Researcher with Hugo Academic</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/project/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/project/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-does-a-researcher-need-a-personal-website&#34;&gt;🌐 Why does a researcher need a personal website?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s academic community, a personal website has become not just a business card, but a full-fledged tool for building a scientific career. It allows you to gather in one place publications, projects, achievements, contact information, and even a blog with reflections on current research. Such a resource simplifies interaction with colleagues, increases the visibility of research results, and strengthens a professional image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-hugo-academic&#34;&gt;🛠 Why Hugo Academic?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is a ready-to-use theme for the Hugo static site generator, specially adapted for the needs of researchers, students, and educators.&lt;br&gt;
Its key advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;Focus on academic activity&lt;/strong&gt;: publications, projects, grants, courses, and achievements are organized into convenient sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⚡ &lt;strong&gt;High performance&lt;/strong&gt;: the site runs on static pages, ensuring fast loading and responsiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎨 &lt;strong&gt;Flexible design&lt;/strong&gt;: you can choose a minimalist style or customize the appearance to fit personal preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌍 &lt;strong&gt;Multilingual support&lt;/strong&gt;: essential for engaging with the international research community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔒 &lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;/strong&gt;: a static site is secure and can be easily hosted on GitHub Pages, Netlify, or any other hosting platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-structure-of-a-researchers-website&#34;&gt;📑 Structure of a researcher’s website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A personal website built with Hugo Academic usually includes several key sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Page&lt;/strong&gt;: brief information about yourself, research interests, and current position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications&lt;/strong&gt;: list of journal articles, monographs, and conference papers with options to add DOIs and links to originals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects&lt;/strong&gt;: descriptions of research work, lab initiatives, and collaborations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching&lt;/strong&gt;: courses, seminars, lectures, and teaching materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awards and Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;: grants, scholarships, prizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog&lt;/strong&gt;: personal notes, academic reflections, and conference reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This structure helps colleagues and students quickly find relevant information and gain a better understanding of the researcher’s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-how-does-it-impact-a-career&#34;&gt;🚀 How does it impact a career?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increases visibility&lt;/strong&gt; — publications and projects become accessible to a wide circle of colleagues and potential partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creates a digital portfolio&lt;/strong&gt; — instead of scattered profiles on various academic networks, you have a unified resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplifies communication&lt;/strong&gt; — contact details and links to ResearchGate, ORCID, Google Scholar, and others are gathered in one place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attracts students and collaborators&lt;/strong&gt; — the site serves as a hub for exchanging ideas and finding co-authors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A personal website built with &lt;strong&gt;Hugo Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is more than just a page on the internet. It is a professional platform that unites research, achievements, and personal interests into a single digital ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of global academic competition, such a resource is no longer a luxury, but a necessity for every modern researcher.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence in Education — Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-is-this-topic-important&#34;&gt;📚 Why is this topic important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence is gradually becoming part of the educational process. From automated grading to personalized recommendations — all of this is changing the way students learn and interact with teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology helps reduce routine tasks, leaving more time for creative and research work. At the same time, however, it brings new challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-opportunities-of-ai-in-education&#34;&gt;🚀 Opportunities of AI in education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalized learning&lt;/strong&gt;: courses adapted to students’ knowledge level and interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligent assistants&lt;/strong&gt;: help with difficult topics and answers to questions 24/7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning analytics&lt;/strong&gt;: tracking progress and identifying problem areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automation of routine tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: test grading, assignment generation, scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New learning formats&lt;/strong&gt;: virtual labs, simulations, and gamified practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-challenges-and-risks&#34;&gt;⚖️ Challenges and risks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependence on technology&lt;/strong&gt;: excessive reliance on AI may reduce critical thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data quality&lt;/strong&gt;: incorrect data can lead to errors in learning systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethical issues&lt;/strong&gt;: privacy, data protection, and algorithmic bias risks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teacher’s role&lt;/strong&gt;: educators must remain mentors, not just moderators of a digital environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-balancing-technology-and-tradition&#34;&gt;🧩 Balancing technology and tradition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI does not replace teachers — it extends their capabilities. The best results are achieved when technology assists but does not substitute human involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A combination of &lt;strong&gt;digital tools&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;live interaction&lt;/strong&gt; creates harmony:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI helps with automation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the teacher preserves an individual approach and motivation for students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence opens tremendous prospects for education: it makes learning more flexible, accessible, and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, success depends on the proper use of technology and the ability to balance it with traditional teaching methods.&lt;br&gt;
The future of education is a partnership between humans and machines, with each playing its unique role.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-is-cicd&#34;&gt;🔄 What is CI/CD?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s software development world, speed and quality of product delivery play a crucial role.&lt;br&gt;
This is where &lt;strong&gt;Continuous Integration (CI)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Continuous Deployment (CD)&lt;/strong&gt; come into play.&lt;br&gt;
These practices automate the process of building, testing, and delivering applications, minimizing errors and accelerating the release of new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-continuous-integration-ci&#34;&gt;⚙️ Continuous Integration (CI)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CI&lt;/strong&gt; is a practice where developers regularly merge their changes into a shared repository.&lt;br&gt;
Each new change automatically goes through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Project build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Automated testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Code quality checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast error detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining stability of the main codebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced time spent on manual verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, developers can spot and fix issues before changes make their way into the production branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-continuous-deployment-cd&#34;&gt;🚀 Continuous Deployment (CD)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CD&lt;/strong&gt; is the next step after CI. It includes the automatic delivery and deployment of code to a production or test environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible CD stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔹 Automatic deployment to a staging environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔹 Manual or automated release approval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔹 Product delivery to end users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster release cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced human error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to quickly roll back changes in case of failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-is-cicd-important&#34;&gt;📈 Why is CI/CD important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;/strong&gt; — new features reach users faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality&lt;/strong&gt; — automated testing reduces the number of bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;/strong&gt; — a stable process lowers risks during updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt; — the whole team can see the current state of development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-cicd-in-modern-development&#34;&gt;🧩 CI/CD in Modern Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CI/CD is not just a set of tools, but part of the &lt;strong&gt;DevOps philosophy&lt;/strong&gt;, which aims to unite development and operations.&lt;br&gt;
These practices help companies stay agile, adapt quickly to changes, and deliver products that meet user expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment have become the industry standard.&lt;br&gt;
CI/CD enables teams to create reliable and high-quality products, reducing the time from idea to implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the era of digital transformation, mastering these processes becomes a key competitive advantage for both companies and IT professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Presentations — From Structure to Visual Delivery</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-are-presentations-important&#34;&gt;🎤 Why are presentations important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation is a tool for conveying ideas, research results, and projects in a clear and visual form.&lt;br&gt;
It helps to structure material, make it more accessible to the audience, and emphasize key points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For students and researchers, presentations are especially important during:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thesis and dissertation defenses,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;academic conferences and seminars,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lectures and teaching sessions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project meetings and collaborations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-structure-of-an-effective-presentation&#34;&gt;📑 Structure of an effective presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation is built on &lt;strong&gt;the logic of storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;. It should guide the audience from the problem statement to the conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic outline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title slide:&lt;/strong&gt; work title, author, date, institution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; relevance of the topic, goals, and objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main part:&lt;/strong&gt; key ideas, methods, results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples/visuals:&lt;/strong&gt; data visualization, charts, illustrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; findings, perspectives, recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contacts:&lt;/strong&gt; feedback and useful links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-visual-style&#34;&gt;🎨 Visual style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visual aspect affects perception just as much as the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalism:&lt;/strong&gt; avoid overloading slides with text, use no more than 6–7 lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fonts:&lt;/strong&gt; clear and readable; at least 18 pt size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colors:&lt;/strong&gt; use contrasting combinations, avoid excessive brightness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Images:&lt;/strong&gt; only relevant and high quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charts and graphs:&lt;/strong&gt; must be understandable without unnecessary labels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-tools-for-creating-presentations&#34;&gt;🛠 Tools for creating presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many platforms, each with its strengths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft PowerPoint&lt;/strong&gt; — a classic and universal tool, suitable for most cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Slides&lt;/strong&gt; — a cloud service for collaborative work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canva&lt;/strong&gt; — a design tool with a large selection of templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LaTeX Beamer&lt;/strong&gt; — for academic presentations with formulas and strict formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prezi&lt;/strong&gt; — dynamic non-linear presentations with zooming effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice depends on the purpose: for a lecture, a strict structure works best; for a conference, brevity; for a creative project, original visual solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-the-art-of-delivery&#34;&gt;📢 The art of delivery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation is not only slides but also &lt;strong&gt;live communication with the audience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehearse in advance, checking timing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t read the slides word for word — they are only a reference outline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use gestures and maintain eye contact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to tone and pace of speech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End the talk with a clear conclusion or an invitation to discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating presentations is a synthesis of &lt;strong&gt;structured content&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;visual literacy&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;public speaking skills&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation does not overwhelm the audience but helps them understand the essence of the research or project, making it memorable and persuasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation is a bridge between the researcher and the audience, which means its quality directly influences the success of the performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markup Languages and the Role of LaTeX in Scientific Communication</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-is-a-markup-language&#34;&gt;🧭 What is a markup language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;markup language&lt;/strong&gt; is a way to structure and describe the content of a document using special commands and tags.&lt;br&gt;
The goal is to separate the &lt;strong&gt;semantic structure&lt;/strong&gt; (headings, lists, formulas, citations, references) from the &lt;strong&gt;presentation&lt;/strong&gt; (fonts, spacing, colors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-advantages-of-markup&#34;&gt;Key advantages of markup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structured content:&lt;/strong&gt; documents are easy to break into logical sections and automatically generate a table of contents, list of figures, and tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility:&lt;/strong&gt; the same source file can be transformed into PDF, HTML, DOCX, and other formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automation:&lt;/strong&gt; references, bibliographies, cross-references, and numbering are generated automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version control:&lt;/strong&gt; plain text is easy to store and track in version control systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-classification-of-markup-languages&#34;&gt;🗂️ Classification of markup languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentational:&lt;/strong&gt; describe &lt;em&gt;how content looks&lt;/em&gt; (historically how early HTML worked).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structural/descriptive:&lt;/strong&gt; focus on the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of elements (modern HTML5, XML, Markdown).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procedural:&lt;/strong&gt; combine structure with typesetting and compilation directives (LaTeX belongs here).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-where-are-markup-languages-used&#34;&gt;🧪 Where are markup languages used?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science and education:&lt;/strong&gt; articles, theses, reports, teaching materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; manuals, specifications, guides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web publishing:&lt;/strong&gt; blog posts, project documentation, presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing industry:&lt;/strong&gt; books, collected volumes, complex layouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-latex-the-de-facto-standard-for-scientific-texts&#34;&gt;🦾 LaTeX: the de facto standard for scientific texts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LaTeX&lt;/strong&gt; is a procedural markup language and document preparation system designed for professional typography, especially where many formulas, tables, figures, and strict formatting are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-makes-latex-stand-out&#34;&gt;What makes LaTeX stand out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-quality typography:&lt;/strong&gt; precise hyphenation, alignment, spacing, mathematical typesetting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced mathematics made easy:&lt;/strong&gt; comprehensive symbol support and clear rendering of complex multi-line formulas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible document structure:&lt;/strong&gt; strict classes and environments for articles, reports, books, and presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; from a two-page note to a monograph with hundreds of figures and references.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensibility:&lt;/strong&gt; thousands of packages for diagrams, algorithms, chemical formulas, glossaries, indexes, multilingual support, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-core-building-blocks-of-latex&#34;&gt;🧱 Core building blocks of LaTeX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document classes:&lt;/strong&gt; standard layouts for articles, reports, books, presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packages:&lt;/strong&gt; add-ons for margins, line spacing, captions, bibliographies, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure:&lt;/strong&gt; sections, subsections, table of contents, lists of figures, appendices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References and citations:&lt;/strong&gt; cross-references to figures, tables, formulas, and sections; integration with bibliography systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figures and tables:&lt;/strong&gt; placement with captions and automatic numbering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multilingual support:&lt;/strong&gt; tools for localization and correct hyphenation (e.g., for Russian or other languages).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-bibliography-and-citation&#34;&gt;📚 Bibliography and citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In academic texts, accurate referencing and consistent formatting of sources is critical.&lt;br&gt;
The LaTeX ecosystem supports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliographic databases&lt;/strong&gt; with metadata (authors, titles, years, DOIs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation styles&lt;/strong&gt; for journals and conferences (numeric, author–year, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic bibliography generation&lt;/strong&gt; and cross-references across the document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-workflows&#34;&gt;🌍 Workflows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud-based:&lt;/strong&gt; collaborative editing in online editors with versioning, comments, and PDF rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local compilation:&lt;/strong&gt; installing distributions, adding packages, managing projects with scripts and build profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version control integration:&lt;/strong&gt; tracking changes, branching for reviews, maintaining history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversion:&lt;/strong&gt; exporting materials into other formats for journals and repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-best-practices&#34;&gt;✅ Best practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single source of truth:&lt;/strong&gt; store text, figures, tables, and bibliography in one project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strict structure:&lt;/strong&gt; consistent use of headings, captions, and formatting styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meaningful filenames:&lt;/strong&gt; clear prefixes for figures, tables, and diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automating repetitive elements:&lt;/strong&gt; templates, autogenerated title pages, tables of contents, glossaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality control:&lt;/strong&gt; regular builds, checking hyphenation, layout issues, references, and numbering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-when-is-latex-especially-useful&#34;&gt;🧩 When is LaTeX especially useful?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large volumes of mathematical formulas and symbols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strict formatting requirements from a journal or university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable workflows for document preparation and peer review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-lived documents with regular updates and reusable parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-alternatives-and-complementary-approaches&#34;&gt;🔄 Alternatives and complementary approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown and other lightweight markup:&lt;/strong&gt; quick drafts, notes, simple documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static site generators:&lt;/strong&gt; publishing academic content online with consistent styling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversion tools:&lt;/strong&gt; single source converted into multiple formats (PDF, HTML, DOCX) with unified styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markup languages provide discipline, automation, and reproducibility in document preparation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;LaTeX&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful standard for academic communication: it allows authors to focus on content while leaving formatting to the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For researchers and students, LaTeX is not just a tool — it is the foundation for well-structured, professional, and high-quality academic texts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Programming Languages — Tools for Research and Computation</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/publication/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-is-scientific-programming&#34;&gt;🔬 What is scientific programming?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientific programming&lt;/strong&gt; is the use of programming languages and tools to solve research-related problems:&lt;br&gt;
process modeling, data analysis, numerical computation, and visualization of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike applied programming, scientific programming emphasizes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;precision and reliability of algorithms,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with large datasets,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for numerical methods and mathematical libraries,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integration with visualization systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-key-requirements-for-languages&#34;&gt;🧩 Key requirements for languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages should provide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High performance&lt;/strong&gt; — for complex calculations and simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematical expressiveness&lt;/strong&gt; — convenient notation for formulas and algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich ecosystem of libraries&lt;/strong&gt; — for linear algebra, statistics, modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portability&lt;/strong&gt; — ability to run code on clusters, supercomputers, and local machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration&lt;/strong&gt; with visualization and analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-major-scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;📚 Major scientific programming languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fortran&#34;&gt;🟢 Fortran&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the oldest languages, still widely used in computational physics and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: high speed, optimization for supercomputers, numerical method libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: fluid dynamics modeling, climate models, physical simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-c-and-c&#34;&gt;🟡 C and C++&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used for high-performance applications where memory control and optimization matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: versatility, numerical libraries, GPU support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: engineering packages, computer modeling systems, simulations in biology and chemistry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-python&#34;&gt;🔵 Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular for its simplicity and rich ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: libraries like NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, TensorFlow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: data analysis, machine learning, scientific experiments, algorithm prototyping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-julia&#34;&gt;🟣 Julia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A modern language designed specifically for scientific computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: combines Python’s simplicity with C’s speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: numerical methods, machine learning, big data processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-matlab&#34;&gt;⚪ MATLAB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A language and environment aimed at engineers and researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: ready-to-use tools for matrices, graphics, visualization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: signal processing, systems control, engineering modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-r&#34;&gt;🟤 R&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main language for statistics and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths: rich packages for visualization and statistical models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications: bioinformatics, sociology, economics, medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-additional-languages-and-environments&#34;&gt;🌍 Additional languages and environments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wolfram Mathematica&lt;/strong&gt; — powerful system for symbolic mathematics and modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maple&lt;/strong&gt; — focused on analytical computation and educational tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; — sometimes used in large-scale scientific projects requiring cross-platform support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CUDA&lt;/strong&gt; (based on C++) — for parallel computations on GPUs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-trends-in-scientific-programming&#34;&gt;📈 Trends in scientific programming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration with machine learning&lt;/strong&gt; (Python, Julia, R).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceleration via GPUs&lt;/strong&gt; (CUDA, OpenCL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multidisciplinary projects&lt;/strong&gt; combining multiple languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth of open-source libraries&lt;/strong&gt; for global scientific collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-conclusion&#34;&gt;✨ Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages form the foundation of modern science.&lt;br&gt;
They allow researchers to model complex systems, process large datasets, and discover new patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of language depends on the task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortran and C++&lt;/strong&gt; — for maximum performance,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python and Julia&lt;/strong&gt; — for flexibility and prototyping,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R and MATLAB&lt;/strong&gt; — for statistics and engineering applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a bridge between theory and practice, helping turn ideas into validated results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the New Academic Year — Plans and Goals</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-23--july-29&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 23 – July 29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vacation is gradually reaching its midpoint, and thoughts are beginning to return to studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was dedicated to planning: I made a list of goals for the upcoming semester, highlighting courses and topics I want to explore further. I plan to focus especially on databases and the English language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-also-tried-keeping-a-study-journal-to-structure-tasks-and-track-progress-vacation-provides-time-to-reflect-which-means-it-also-helps-prepare-for-new-achievements&#34;&gt;I also tried keeping a study journal to structure tasks and track progress. Vacation provides time to reflect, which means it also helps prepare for new achievements.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trip to Nature — Balancing Study and Rest</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-16--july-22&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 16 – July 22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was spent outdoors — together with friends we went out of town. It felt great to change the environment after the stressful exams and the hustle of city life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A campfire, forest walks, and late-night conversations helped me reset. I even managed to solve a couple of programming problems on my laptop — the brain keeps seeking activity anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;such-a-balance--rest-combined-with-a-bit-of-study--turned-out-to-be-very-beneficial&#34;&gt;Such a balance — rest combined with a bit of study — turned out to be very beneficial.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer in the City — Meetings and New Impressions</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-9--july-15&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 9 – July 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week the vacation became more active. I met with classmates, we walked around Moscow together and discussed our plans for the upcoming academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also visited a digital technology exhibition — it was fascinating to see real examples of how artificial intelligence and automation are applied in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-addition-i-started-exploring-new-hobbies-digital-drawing-and-listening-to-english-podcasts-the-vacation-is-becoming-not-only-a-time-for-rest-but-also-an-opportunity-to-grow-in-areas-that-truly-inspire-me&#34;&gt;In addition, I started exploring new hobbies: digital drawing and listening to English podcasts. The vacation is becoming not only a time for rest, but also an opportunity to grow in areas that truly inspire me.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Days of Vacation — Rest After a Stressful Exam Session</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-2--july-8&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 2 – July 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exam session is behind me, and now I can finally take a breath. The first days of vacation are all about well-deserved rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the week I spent at home — catching up on sleep and enjoying the freedom of having no strict schedule. At last, I had time to read books outside the academic program and spend quality moments with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vacation-has-just-begun-and-there-are-plenty-of-plans-ahead-trips-new-hobbies-and-self-development&#34;&gt;The vacation has just begun, and there are plenty of plans ahead: trips, new hobbies, and self-development.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam Session — The First Major Test of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-june-25--july-1&#34;&gt;📌 Week of June 25 – July 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week marked the most intense part of the academic year — the exam session.&lt;br&gt;
The exams turned out to be a serious challenge: preparing for economics and programming was especially demanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the stress, it was rewarding to realize that the knowledge is gradually forming into a coherent system. A lot of time was spent in the library, consulting with professors, and solving problems together with classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-most-important-thing-is-that-i-managed-to-cope-and-gained-valuable-experience-that-will-be-useful-in-my-further-studies&#34;&gt;The most important thing is that I managed to cope and gained valuable experience that will be useful in my further studies.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/teaching/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/teaching/js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Blox Builder&lt;/a&gt; is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili id=&amp;quot;BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&amp;rsquo;s folder&lt;/a&gt;, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$...${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$$...$${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;We wrap the LaTeX math in the Hugo Blox &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to prevent Hugo rendering our math as Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;

$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$


&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;


$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$



&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
