<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Student | Nuhova Kamila Ruslanovna</title>
    <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/tags/student/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://krnuhova.github.io/en/tags/student/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Student</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://krnuhova.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Student</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/tags/student/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the New Academic Year — Plans and Goals</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-23--july-29&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 23 – July 29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vacation is gradually reaching its midpoint, and thoughts are beginning to return to studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was dedicated to planning: I made a list of goals for the upcoming semester, highlighting courses and topics I want to explore further. I plan to focus especially on databases and the English language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-also-tried-keeping-a-study-journal-to-structure-tasks-and-track-progress-vacation-provides-time-to-reflect-which-means-it-also-helps-prepare-for-new-achievements&#34;&gt;I also tried keeping a study journal to structure tasks and track progress. Vacation provides time to reflect, which means it also helps prepare for new achievements.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trip to Nature — Balancing Study and Rest</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-16--july-22&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 16 – July 22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was spent outdoors — together with friends we went out of town. It felt great to change the environment after the stressful exams and the hustle of city life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A campfire, forest walks, and late-night conversations helped me reset. I even managed to solve a couple of programming problems on my laptop — the brain keeps seeking activity anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;such-a-balance--rest-combined-with-a-bit-of-study--turned-out-to-be-very-beneficial&#34;&gt;Such a balance — rest combined with a bit of study — turned out to be very beneficial.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer in the City — Meetings and New Impressions</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-9--july-15&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 9 – July 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week the vacation became more active. I met with classmates, we walked around Moscow together and discussed our plans for the upcoming academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also visited a digital technology exhibition — it was fascinating to see real examples of how artificial intelligence and automation are applied in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-addition-i-started-exploring-new-hobbies-digital-drawing-and-listening-to-english-podcasts-the-vacation-is-becoming-not-only-a-time-for-rest-but-also-an-opportunity-to-grow-in-areas-that-truly-inspire-me&#34;&gt;In addition, I started exploring new hobbies: digital drawing and listening to English podcasts. The vacation is becoming not only a time for rest, but also an opportunity to grow in areas that truly inspire me.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Days of Vacation — Rest After a Stressful Exam Session</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-july-2--july-8&#34;&gt;📌 Week of July 2 – July 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exam session is behind me, and now I can finally take a breath. The first days of vacation are all about well-deserved rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the week I spent at home — catching up on sleep and enjoying the freedom of having no strict schedule. At last, I had time to read books outside the academic program and spend quality moments with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vacation-has-just-begun-and-there-are-plenty-of-plans-ahead-trips-new-hobbies-and-self-development&#34;&gt;The vacation has just begun, and there are plenty of plans ahead: trips, new hobbies, and self-development.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam Session — The First Major Test of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krnuhova.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-june-25--july-1&#34;&gt;📌 Week of June 25 – July 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week marked the most intense part of the academic year — the exam session.&lt;br&gt;
The exams turned out to be a serious challenge: preparing for economics and programming was especially demanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the stress, it was rewarding to realize that the knowledge is gradually forming into a coherent system. A lot of time was spent in the library, consulting with professors, and solving problems together with classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-most-important-thing-is-that-i-managed-to-cope-and-gained-valuable-experience-that-will-be-useful-in-my-further-studies&#34;&gt;The most important thing is that I managed to cope and gained valuable experience that will be useful in my further studies.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
